http://www.hazeldenbettyford.org/privacy

Skip to content
We're open, taking patients and expanding virtual services. Learn more >>
Please read carefully before using this Website
Your privacy on the Internet is important to us. The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to let you know what information we collect through this Web site, how we collect, use and share that information, and how you may view, correct or change the information if you should desire to do so.
Scope of this Privacy Policy
This Privacy Policy applies only to information collected on or through the websites owned and operated by the Hazelden Betty Ford Foundation ("Hazelden Betty Ford"). Any specific web site, including all subordinate web pages, owned and operated by Hazelden Betty Ford is referred to as a "Site" or "Website." Hazelden Betty Ford may engage third parties such as a hosting service to assist in the operation of any Website including the Website through which you linked to view this Privacy Policy. As used in this Privacy Policy, the terms "we," "us" and "our" refer to the Hazelden Betty Ford Foundation.
The information practices of other sites operated or maintained by the Hazelden Betty Ford Foundation or by any third party are not covered by this Privacy Policy. By your use of the Website, “You” (the person using this Web site on behalf of yourself, as well as on behalf of any other person or entity on whose behalf of for whose benefit you are using the Web site) agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy, including any changes to the Privacy Policy. If any portion of this Privacy Policy is unacceptable to you, do not use the Website. Use of the Website constitutes acceptance of this Privacy Policy.
Your use of this Website is also governed by our Website Terms of Use
Privacy Practices Notice - Health Information
Certain protected health information that may be provided by You is protected as described in Hazelden Betty Ford’s Privacy Practices Notice. In the event of any conflict between the terms of this Privacy Policy and the terms of the Privacy Practices Notice, the terms of the Privacy Practices Notice shall control.
Information Collected
The type of information collected on this Website will depend upon the features and functionalities available on this Website, which may be revised from time to time. For example, if this Website is currently operated as a “read-only” web site, we may not collect any personal information about you through the Website and will not learn who you are. On the other hand, if this Website permits you to "register," "create an account," make purchases, or take similar actions, we will collect information from you that can be used to specifically identify you as an individual (such as your name, telephone number, postal address, email address, and payment information, collectively "Personal Data"). This Web site also automatically collects aggregated information that is not linked to any specific individual such as information about traffic patterns on the Website, or the number of times a specific page was viewed in a particular month. We may use and share aggregate, de-identified, and anonymous data without restriction as it does not identify you or any other individual user.
Personal Data, Use and Sharing
If this Website permits you to register, create an account, make purchases, or take similar actions, and if you chose to take such actions, then we will ask you to provide us with certain Personal Data about yourself. It is always your choice whether you wish to provide Personal Data through this Website, but if you do not provide requested Personal Data you may not be able to use all the features or functionalities of this Website.
Personal Data may be combined with other information we receive through other methods, such as from you in-person if you visit one of our facilities. Personal Data will not be sold or given to third parties for marketing purposes except in the limited cases described elsewhere in this Privacy Policy (for example we may transfer Personal Data to a successor organization). We reserve the right to share your Personal Data with third parties if we determine, in our sole discretion, that such action is necessary to comply with legal requirements or with legal process served upon us, or to protect the safety of you, members of the public, other users of this Website, or any other person, or to protect the Hazelden Betty Ford Foundation’s rights. We also may use and/or share Personal Data with third parties that help us operate our business, for example we may provide your email address to an email vendor that helps us send large volumes of email, and if you make a purchase we may share your Personal Data with third parties as necessary to process your order and receive payment. We may share Personal Data with The Hazelden Betty Ford Foundation’s affiliate and subsidiary entities. The Hazelden Betty Ford Foundation may transfer Personal Data to a successor entity such as in the case of a sale of our business, a particular business division, merger, spin-off, sale of substantially all assets, or a similar transaction. The Hazelden Betty Ford Foundation may use Personal Data to provide requested services to you and to provide you with additional information we believe you may find interesting or useful. Depending upon the features of this Website, we may use Personal Data to track your activities / progress on and through this Web site, as well as purchases made through this site or other transaction history. We may contact you through any and all contact methods (e.g., cell phone, fax, email, etc.) you provide us through this Website.
Reviewing and Changing Personal Data
The Website, now or in the future, may provide the ability for you to view, in-activate and or update the Personal Data you have submitted. If such functionality is available, on a specific Website, click on the link or page to "sign in," view your "account," or similar link or heading. Note, due to the nature of third party hardware, software and other third party tools, even when information is corrected or de-activated, an archive or other copy may remain.
Use of Cookies
The Web site does use cookies in a limited manner. A cookie is a small data file that most major Websites write to your hard drive for record-keeping purposes when you visit them. Cookies allow Website managers to measure activity on the site and to improve your user experience, for example, by remembering your passwords and viewing preferences, thus allowing you to visit various registered access parts of the site without re-registering.
These cookies are not created or used to collect any information (aggregate or personal) about you at any time. You may occasionally get cookies from other sites, which is standard in the Internet industry. The Hazelden Betty Ford Foundation does not control these cookies, and these cookies are not subject to this Privacy Policy.
You do not have to accept cookies to use our Website, however, you may not be able to use certain features or access certain areas if you do not accept cookies. Although most browsers are initially set to accept cookies, you may reset your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie or to reject cookies generally.
Public Forums
This Website, now or in the future, may include public forums such as message boards, bulletin boards, chat rooms, or similar activities through which users of the Website can communicate with one another. THIS PRIVACY POLICY DOES NOT PROTECT YOU WHEN YOU USE PUBLIC FORUMS OR PROVIDE INFORMATION (INCLUDING PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION) ABOUT YOURSELF. You should be aware that any information shared in a public forum such as a message board, bulletin board, chat room, or other forum is public information and may be seen by third parties that do not adhere to our Privacy Policy. You should think carefully before disclosing any information in any public forum, including the forums on our Website.
Social Media and Third Party Platforms
Certain sections or functionalities on this Website may permit you to choose to cross-post or share information on a third party social media site or platform such as Facebook, Instagram, LinkedIn, Twitter, Google+, or other similar sites (collectively, "Social Media Sites"). The Hazelden Betty Ford Foundation does not own or control such Social Media Sites, and posting your information on Social Media Sites is subject to the third party’s privacy policy and other legal terms, which may or may not provide privacy protections with which you agree. The Hazelden Betty Ford Foundation is not responsible for any act or omission of any Social Media Site, nor are we responsible for the consequences of your choosing to share your information on Social Media Sites.
Security
The Website has security measures in place designed to protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. However, data transmission over the Internet or wireless networks cannot be guaranteed to be completely secure. Although we are committed to safeguarding your privacy and security, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us, and you do so at your own risk. The Hazelden Betty Ford Foundation is not responsible or liable for the illegal acts (such as hacking) of third parties.
Links to Other Websites
This Website may contain links to other web sites and those sites may not follow the same privacy policies as Hazelden Betty Ford. These sites may send their own cookies to you, and may collect and use data in ways that Hazelden Betty Ford would not. Please note that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of third party Websites. We encourage you to be aware of this when you leave our Website and to read the privacy policies of every Web site that collects personally identifiable information from you. The Privacy Policy applies only to this Website.
Children’s Privacy
We are committed to protecting the privacy of children. The interactive features of our Website are not designed for or directed to children under the age of 17. The Hazelden Betty Ford Foundation shall not be liable for any unauthorized use of the Website by minors. Please contact us if you believe a child under the age of 13 has provided Personal Data to this Website without parental consent.
Use of Website
Your access to and use of the Website are subject to certain terms and conditions, which are contained in our Terms of Use.
Contacting this Website
If you want to review or revise the personal information you provided during registration on the Web site, sign in to your account to update any information. Or, if you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this Web site, or your dealings with this Web site, you can contact us by email at webmaster@hazeldenbettyford.org.
Download and read our Notice of Privacy Practices.
Are you or a loved one struggling with alcohol or other drugs?
Call toll-free to speak confidentially with a recovery expert now.
Most insurance accepted. Call to check benefits.
1-866-831-5700
Read More
Together We Will Overcome Addiction
Podcast: Mark Mishek talks about parity, partnerships and public awareness—progress that translates ...
Read More
>
Read More
Twelve Step Spiritual Principles
Misconceptions about the 12 Step Program of Recovery
Read More
>
Read More
12 Steps Mental Health
The Twelve Steps of AA can offer a path to better mental health
Read More
>
Your gift can change people's lives.
Donate Today
The Hazelden Betty Ford Foundation is a force of healing and hope for individuals, families and communities affected by addiction to alcohol and other drugs. As the nation's leading nonprofit provider of comprehensive inpatient and outpatient treatment for adults and youth, the Foundation has 17 locations nationwide and collaborates with an expansive network throughout health care. With a legacy that began in 1949 and includes the 1982 founding of the Betty Ford Center, the Foundation today also encompasses a graduate school of addiction studies, a publishing division, an addiction research center, recovery advocacy and thought leadership, professional and medical education programs, school-based prevention resources and a specialized program for children who grow up in families with addiction.
